Guide to the Irving S. Olds Collection of Naval and Other Historical Prints and Related Papers 1587-1960 PR 47
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Prints & Related Papers from the Original Olds Donation, 1587-1960, undated; 17.63 Linear feet in 33 flat file folders and 6 boxes
  - Subseries I.A. Prints and Other Documents from the Olds Collection, 1587-1921, undated; 16 Linear feet in flat files and three boxes
    - Print No. 98. Engraving: "A View of the American Frigate, Constellation, capturing the French National Frigate L'Insurgente within sight of Basseterre, Feby. 9th. 1799…", 1800 (Folder FF-2)
      Published by John Fairburn, London, Oct. 1, 1800. See No. 358 post.
    - Olds Catalogue Section E. War With Tripoli (Folder -)
    - Print No. 101. Lithograph: "The U.S. Frigate Philadelphia On The Rocks Off Tripoli. Oct. 31st 1801.", 1840 (Folder FF-2)
      Lithographed by P.S. Duval, Phila. On Stone by E.J. Pinkerton. From the U.S. Military Magazine, November 1840. First state.
    - Print No. 102. Aquatint: "Burning of the Frigate Philadelphia in the Harbour of Tripoli..., undated (Folder FF-13)
      Full title: "Burning of the Frigate Philadelphia in the Harbour of Tripoli, 16th. Feb. 1804, by 70 Gallant Tars of Columbia commanded by Lieut. Decatur." Artist and engraver not named. Second state.
    - Print No. 103. Aquatint: "Nautical Exploit, Dedicated to Commodore Ed. Preble... The American Ketch Intrepid... commanded by Lieutenant Decatur, boarding and burning the Tripolitan Frigate (late the Philadelphia) in the middle of the harbour of Tripoli... on the night of the 16th. of February 1804.", undated (Folder FF-29)
      Drawn by L. Binsse. Engraved by Aubertin.
    - Print No. 104. Engraving: "The burning of the American Fregate the Philadelphia in the Harbour of Tripoli.. .", 1805 (Folder FF-2)
      Dedicated by John B. Guerrazzi. Sold in Leghorn 1805.
    - Print No. 107. Engraving: "The attack made on Tripoli on the 3d. August 1804. by the American Squadron under Commodore Edward Preble …", 1805 (Folder FF-2)
      Dedicated by John B. Guerrazzi. Sold in Leghorn 1805. First state.
    - Print No. 108. Engraving: "The attack made on Tripoli on the 3d August 1804. by the American Squadron under Comodore Edward Preble.. .", 1805 (Folder FF-2)
      Dedicated by John B. Guerrazzi. Sold in Leghorn 1805. Second state, with key.
    - Print No. 109. Lithograph: "August 1804. Bombardment of Tripoli"., 1846 (Folder FF-2)
      Lithographed & Published by N. Currier. Copyrighted 1846.
    - Print No. 112. Engraving: "Blowing Up of the Fire Ship Intrepid...", undated (Folder FF-13)
      Full title: "Blowing Up of the Fire Ship Intrepid commanded by Capt. Somers in the Harbour of Tripoli on the night of 4th Sepr. 1804." Artist and engraver not named. Illustration from "The Port Folio", December 1810. In black and white.
    - Print No. 112A. Engraving: "Blowing Up of the Fire Ship Intrepid...", undated (Folder FF-13)
      Full title: "Blowing Up of the Fire Ship Intrepid commanded by Capt. Somers in the Harbour of Tripoli on the night of 4th Sepr. 1804." Artist and engraver not named. Illustration from "The Port Folio", December 1810. Print No. 112A is the same as the foregoing print (No. 112), except colored by hand.
    - Olds Catalogue Section F. Little Belt Incident (Folder -)
    - Print No. 113. Aquatint: "The Little Belt, Sloop of War...", 1811 (Folder FF-22)
      Full title: "The Little Belt, Sloop of War, Captn. Bingham nobly supporting the Honor of the British Flag, against the President United States Frigate, Commodore Rogers, May 15th. 1811." Drawn, engraved and published by Wm. Elmes. Sold October 25, 1811 by Edwd. Orme, London.
    - Print No. 114. Aquatint: Print dedicated to Charles Philip Yorke, 1811 (Folder FF-7)
      Print dedicated to Charles Philip Yorke "elucidating the extreme disproportion of Force between the American Frigate President Commodore Rodgers, and His Majesty's Sloop the Little Belt Arthur Butt Bingham Esquire Commander, and representing the situation of both Ships in the morning after the Action of 11 May 1811…" Drawn by J. Cartwright. Engraved by J. Hassell. Published London, December 1, 1811.
    - Print No. 115. Proof before letters of the foregoing aquatint (No. 114), undated (Folder FF-7)
      Proof before letters of the foregoing aquatint of the morning after the action between the American Frigate President and His Majesty's Sloop Little Belt on May 11, 1811. Drawn by J. Cartwright. Engraved by J. Hassell.
    - Olds Catalogue Section G. War of 1812 (Folder -)
    - Print No. 116. Lithograph: "Belvidera & President", undated (Folder FF-2)
      Lithographed after the drawing by Lieutenant John Allan Wright, R.N.
    - Print No. 117. British lithograph: "Escape Of The Belvidere, Commanded by the Late Adml. Rd. Byron C.B. from the American Squadron.", undated (Folder FF-22)
      Artist, engraver and publisher not named on this copy.
    - Print No. 118. Lithograph: "Combat soutenu le 23 Aout 1812, par la Frégate des Etats Unis d'Amérique le Président, et la Fregate Anglaise Le Belveder"., undated (Folder FF-2)
      Lithographed by L.J. Auger.
    - Print No. 120. Engraving: "This Representation Of The U.S. Frigate Constitution, Isaac Hull, Esqr. Commander, Capturing His Britannic Majesty's Frigate Guerriere, James R. Dacres Esqr. Commander …", 1813 (Folder FF-7)
      Vignette of Captain Hull at base. Painted by T. Birch. Engraved by C. Tiebout. Inscribed by James Webster. Copyrighted August 18, 1813, by James Webster. Colored by hand.
    - Print No. 121. Engraving: "This Representation Of The U.S. Frigate Constitution, Isaac Hull, Esqr. Commander, Capturing His Britannic Majesty's Frigate Guerriere, James R. Dacres Esqr. Commander …", 1813 (Folder FF-33)
      Vignette of Captain Hull at base. Painted by T. Birch. Engraved by C. Tiebout. Inscribed by James Webster. Published August 19, 1813, by James Webster. Copyrighted August 5, 1813, by James Webster. Believed to be an earlier state than the foregoing print.
    - Print No. 123. Aquatint: "Engagement between the U.S. Frigate Constitution & the British Frigate Guerriere; August 19th 1812…", undated (Folder FF-2)
      Full title: "Engagement between the U.S. Frigate Constitution Capt. Hull rating 44 Guns & the British Frigate Guerriere Capt. Dacres rated 38 Guns; August 19th 1812…" Aquatinted by F. Kearney after a drawing by T. Birch. Published by F. Kearny, Philadelphia.
    - Print No. 124. Engraving: "Brilliant Naval Victory", 1812 (Folder FF-2)
      Full title: "Brilliant Naval Victory, With the U. States Frigate Constitution of 44 Guns, Capn. Hull, & the English Frigate Guerriere of 38 Guns, Capn. D'acres, in which action Capn Hull lost 7 men killed, & 7 wounded & his B.M. Ship was sunk, besides her loss of 15 men killed, 62 wounded, & 24 missing; August 20, 1812. After closing the action was 30 minutes." Drawn and engraved by S. Seymour. Published at Philadelphia by J. Pierie & F. Kearney, 1812.
    - Print No. 125. Engraving: "Signal Naval Victory, Achieved by Capt. Hull, of the U.S. Frigate Constitution, over H.B. Majesty's Frigate Guerriere Capt. Dacres…", 1812 (Folder FF-2)
      Designed, engraved & published by W. Strickland & W. Kneass, Philadelphia, September 21, 1812.
    - Print No. 126. Engraving (colored): "Engagement between the U.S. Frigate Constitution Captn. Isaac Hull, & the British Frigate Guerriere, Captn. James R. Dacres, Thursday 19th. August 1812." (Box 2)
      The first of a pair of prints engraved by Benjamin Tanner after drawings by John James Barralet. Published Oct. 1, 1812, by B. Tanner, Philadelphia. First state.
    - Print No. 127. Engraving: "Explosion of the British Frigate, Guerriere, James R. Dacres, Esqr. Captn. and Rescue of the Prisoners, &c. the day after her Capture by the U.S. Frigate Constitution Isaac Hull Esqr. Commr. Friday 20th. August 1812." (Box 2)
      The second of a pair of prints engraved by Benjamin Tanner after drawings by John James Barralet. Published Nov. 10, 1812 by B. Tanner, Philadelphia. First state. Monted on frame board.
    - Print No. 128. Engraving: "The U.S. frigate Constitution... Captured his B.M. frigate Guerriere...", undated (Folder FF-2)
      Full title: The U.S. frigate Constitution Commanded by Isaac Hull, Esqr. Captured his B.M. frigate Guerriere Capt. Dacres In 30 Minutes On the 19th. of August 1812." Pubd. by Chs. D. Veechio, 136 Broad Way. Second state of this engraving, which was originally designed, engraved and published by Thomas Gimbrede.
    - Print No. 128A. Engraving: "The U.S. frigate Constitution Commanded ... Captured his B.M. frigate Guerriere ...", undated (Folder FF-2)
      Full Title: "The U.S. frigate Constitution Commanded by Isaac Hull, Esqr. Captured his B.M. frigate Guerriere Capt. Dacres In 30 Minutes On the 19th. of August 1812." Another state of the foregoing print 128 by Thomas Gimbrede of the action between the Constitution and the Guerriere, with slightly larger engraved surface and probably issued without publication data.
    - Print No. 129. Aquatint: "Plate 1st. Preparing for an Engagement...", 1812 (Folder FF-2)
      Full title: "Plate 1st. Preparing for an Engagement. The Constitution clearing for Action & bearing down. La Guerriere Laying too." Painted by "Michael Carneé under Directions from Commodore Hull & Capt. Morris." Engraved by J.R. Smith, Boston. Published Nov. 1, 1812. The first of a set of three prints.
    - Print No. 130. Engraving: "Prise de la frégate anglaise la Guerriere, par le frégate américaine la Constitution…", undated (Folder FF-7)
      Drawn by Montardier, Havre. Engraved by Baugean. Published by Jean, Paris. First state.
    - Print No. 131. Lithograph: "La Constitution Et La Guerrière + The Constitution and The Guerriere.", undated (Folder FF-7)
      Lithographed by Betremieux. Published by Lordereau, Paris. One of a pair of prints. See No. 170 (Lithograph: "Les Eats Unis Et le Macedonian + The United States and The Macedonian.")
    - Print No. 132. Engraving: "Prise d'un Vaisseau Anglais par un Vaisseau Américain", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Engraved by Debucourt. Represents the action between the Constitution and the Guerriere. See Nos. 171 and 188 (Same engraver, War of 1812 naval battles)
    - Print No. 133. Aquatint: "La Frégate Américaine...", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Full title: "La Frégate Américaine La Constitution Prenant à l'abordage, La Frégate Anglaise, La Guerriere. Apres 30 minutes de Combat, le 19 Aout 1812." Engraved by Valnest after pairing by Stradonwort. Published by Basset, Paris.
    - Print No. 138. Lithograph: "The Constitution And Guerriere. Fought August 19th 1812…", 1846 (Folder FF-10)
      Lithographed and published by N. Currier. Copyrighted 1846 by Sarony & Major.
    - Print No. 139. Lithograph: "The Constitution And Guerriere. Fought August 19. 1812…", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Lithographed and published by N. Currier.
    - Print No. 140. Lithograph: "The capture and destruction of H.B.M. Frigate Guerriere...", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Full title: "The capture and destruction of H.B.M. Frigate Guerriere by the U.S. frigate Constitution. After an action of 30 minutes…American loss 7 killed, 7 wounded. British loss 15 killed, 62 wounded, 24 missing.." Published by N. Currier.
    - Print No. 141. Lithograph: "The capture and destruction of H.B.M. Frigate Guerriere...", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Full title: "The capture and destruction of H.B.M. Frigate Guerriere by the U.S. frigate Constitution. After an action of 30 minutes…American loss 7 killed, 7 wounded. British loss 15 killed, 62 wounded, 24 missing.." Artist, lithographer and publisher not named. View identical with foregoing print (No. 140).
    - Print No. 142. Lithograph: "The Constitution And Guerriere. Fought August 19. 1812…", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Lith. Of E.C. Kellogg.
    - Print No. 143. Lithograph: "Combat between the Frigate Constitution & the British Frigate Guerriere.", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Lith. of D.W. Kellogg & Co. Print No. 1085 is the same print in sepia and colored.black & white.
    - Print No. 143A. Lithograph: "Combat between the Frigate Constitution & the British Frigate Guerriere.", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Perhaps another state of foregoing print (No. 143), with traces of a publication line.
    - Print No. 148. Aquatint, colored: "The Capture of H.B.M. Sloop of War Frolic, Capt. Whinyates, by the U.S. Sloop of War Wasp, Capn. Jab. Jones, on the 18th. of Octr. 1812, after a close Action of 43 Minutes…", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Drawn & Engraved by F. Kearny, from a Sketch by Lieut. Claxton, of the Wasp. Published by F. Kearney, Philadelphia. First state.
    - Print No. 153. Engraving: "Prise de la corvette anglais Forlic par la corvette américaine Wasp...", undated (Folder FF-13)
      Full title: "Prise de la corvette anglais Forlic par la corvette américaine Wasp. The English sloop of war Forlic captur'd By the american sloop of war Wasp." Drawn by Montardier, Havre. Engraved by Baugean, Published by Jean, Paris.
    - Print No. 158. Engraving, colored. "Capture of H.B.M. Frigate Macedonian, Captn. John S. Carden, by the U.S. Frigate United States, Stephen Decatur Esqr. Commander", 1813 (Folder FF-29)
      Painted by T. Birch. Published by B. Tanner, Philadelpia.
    - Print No. 159. Engraving: "Capture of H.B.M. Frigate Macedonian, Captn. John S. Carden by the U.S. Frigate United States, Stephen Decatur Esqr. Commander…", 1813 (Folder FF-7)
      Painted by T. Birch. Engraved and published on October 25, 1813 by B. Tanner, Philadelphia. Second state of the foregoing print (No. 158, not in N-YHS collection), with the same title. J. Webster added as a co-publisher with Benjamin Tanner.
    - Print No. 160. Engraving: "United States and Macedonian…", 1813 (Folder FF-33)
      Painted by T. Birch. Engraved by B. Tanner. Published November 1, 1814 by B. Tanner, Philadelphia. Copyrighted August 13, 1813 by Benjamin Tanner. First state.
    - Print No. 161. Engraving: "United States and Macedonian…", undated (Folder FF-7)
      Second state of the foregoing print (No. 160), with the same title. Painted by T. Birch. Engraved by B. Tanner. Omits publication and copyright data. (See No. 844.)
    - Print No. 163. Second state of No. 162, with the same title ["This Representation of the U.S. Frigate United States, Stephen Decatur Esqr. Commander, Capturing His Brittanic Majesty's Frigate Macedonian, John S. Carden Esqr. Commander…". No. 162 is not in N-YHS collection], undated (Folder FF-7)
      Painted by T. Birch, Engraved by S. Seymour. No. 163 omits publication line. In black and white.
    - Print No. 164. Aquatint: "Capture of H.B.M. Frigate Macedonian 38 Guns Capt. Carden. By the Frigate United States 44 Guns Commodore Decatur…", undated (Folder FF-13)
      Drawn by J.J. Barralett. Engraved by S. Seymour. Published at Philadelphia by W.H. Morgan.
    - Print No. 169. Engraving: "Prise de la frégate anglaise Macédonian, par la frégate américaine united States….", undated (Folder FF-7)
    - Print No. 170. Lithograph: "Les Eats Unis Et le Macedonian + The United States and The Macedonian.", undated (Folder FF-7)
      Lithographed by Betremieux. Published by Lordereau, Paris. First state, before spelling of "Eats" corrected. One of a pair of prints. See No. 131. (Lithograph: "La Constitution Et La Guerrière + The Constitution and The Guerriere.")
    - Print No. 171. Engraving: "Prise de Feu au Vaisseau Anglais dans le Combat navale.", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Engraved by Debucourt. Represents the action between the United States and the Macedonian. See Nos. 132 and 188 (Same engraver, War of 1812 naval battles)
    - Print No. 172. Lithograph: "Seetreffen Zwischen Dem Amerikanischen Schiffe United States Und Dem Brittischen Schiffe Macedonian….", undated (Folder FF-7)
      Lithographed by Franz Kretzchmann. Drawn by W. Wörtner. Published, Rud. Weber, Leipzic. In black and white.
    - Print No. 174. Lithograph: "The U.S. Frigate United States Capturing H.B.M. Frigate Macedonian. Fought Octr. 25th. 1812.", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Lithographed & published by N. Currier, N.Y.
    - Print No. 175. Lithograph: "The U.S. Frigate United States Capturing H.B.M. Frigate Macedonian. Fought, Octr. 25th. 1812.", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Kelloggs & Thayer, 144 Fulton St., N.Y.
    - Print No. 176. Lithograph: "The U.S. Frigate United States Capturing H.B.M. Frigate Macedonian. Fought, Octr. 25th. 1812.", undated (Folder FF-10)
      Lith. of Kellogg & Hanmer, Hartford, Conn.
    - Print No. 181. Aquatint: "Plate 1. Situation of His Majesty's Frigate Java, Captain Lambert, at 5 Min. past 3 P.M. after an hours close & severe Action with the American Frigate Constitution….", 1814 (Folder FF-29)
      Drawn & etched by N. Pocock from a sketch by Lieut. Buchanan. Engraved by R. & D. Havell. Published January 1, 1814 by Boydell & Co., London. One of a set of four prints. (See Nos. 937-940.)
    - Print No. 182. Aquatint: "Plate 2nd. The Java, as she appeared at 35 Min. past 4 P.M. after having sustained several raking Broadsides from the Constitution whilst closely engageing her, until she became a perfect Wreck…", 1814 (Folder FF-29)
    - Print No. 183. Aquatint: "Plate 3d. The Java totally dismasted endeavouring to Wear by the assistance of a Jury Staysail…; the Constitution Crossing her Bow in a Raking Position, Compels her to Surrden at 50 Min. past 5.", 1814 (Folder FF-29)
      Drawn & etched by N. Pocock from a sketch by Leiut. Buchanan. Engraved by R. & D. Havell. Published January 1, 1814 by Boydell & Co., London. One of a set of four prints. (See Nos. 937-940.)
    - Print No. 184. Aquatint: "Plate 4th. The Java in a Sinking state, set fire to, & Blowing up…", 1814 (Folder FF-29)
    - Print No. 185. Aquatint: "To Commodore Bainbridge...", undated (Folder FF-3)
      Full title: "To Commodore Bainbridge the officers Seamen & Marines of the United States frigate Constitution this view of their Glorious capturing the British frigate the Java off the coast of Brazils on the 29th xber 1812 after a Sanguinary conflict of 1 hour & 55 minutes is with respect dedicated to them & the sons of freedom by an admirer of American valour & patriotism." Drawn under the direction of a witness of the action by W.G.
    - Print No. 186. Aquatint: "Le Combat Naval. – Gloire Américaine. Prise glorieuse, du Vaisseau Anglais la Java, par la constitution, frégate Americaine, sur les cotes du Brézil …", undated (Folder FF-29)
      Drawn by Garneray. Engraved by Coqueret. Published by Bulla, Paris. Second state. (See No. 845.)
    - Print No. 188. Engraving: "Batiment Anglais prit par Vaisseau Américain.", undated (Folder FF-3)
      Engraved by Debucourt. Represents the action between the Constitution and the Java. See Nos. 132 (Engraved by Debucourt. Represents the action between the Constitution and the Guerriere) and 171 (Engraved by Debucourt. Represents the action between the United States and the Macedonian) supra.
    - Print No. 190. Engraving, colored: "Prise de la frégate anglaise Java, par la frégate américaine la Constitution …", undated (Folder FF-29)
      Engraved by Baujean. Published by Jean, Paris. Second state, omitting reference to Montardier, Havre.
    - Print No. 191. Lithograph: "Constitution And Java. Fought Dec. 29th. 1812…", 1845 (Folder FF-3)
      Published at C. Currier's, N.Y. Copyrighted 1845 by N. Currier.
    - Print No. 192. Lithograph: "Constitution And Java. Fought Dec. 29th. 1812…", 1846 (Folder FF-3)
      Lithographed and published by N. Currier. Copyrighted 1846 by N. Currier. First state.
    - Print No. 193. Lithograph: "Constitution And Java. Fought Dec. 29th. 1812…", 1846 (Folder FF-3)
      Lithographed and published by N. Currier. Copyrighted 1846 by N. Currier. Second state of foregoing print (192), with coarser lines.
    - Print No. 194. Lithograph: "Constitution And Java. Fought Dec. 29th. 1812…", 1846 (Folder FF-3)
      Lithographed and published by N. Currier. Copyrighted 1846 by N. Currier. Third state of foregoing print (192); a late impression, partially printed in colors.
    - Print No. 195. Lithograph: "The capture of H.B.M. frigate Java; by the U.S. frigate Constitution, after an action of 1 hour, 55 minutes…", 1846 (Folder FF-13)
      Lithographed and published by Sarony & Major, New York. Copyrighted 1846 by Sarony & Major.
    - Print No. 201. Aquatint: "This View of his Majesty's Ship Shannon, hove too, & cooly waiting the close approach of the American Frigate Chesapeak, who is bearing down to the Attack…", 1813 (Folder FF-29)
      Painted by R. Dodd from the information of Captn. Falkinir. Published August 1813 by R. Dodd and G. Andrews. First state. One of a pair of prints. Colored by hand.
    - Print No. 202. Aquatint: "To Captain P.B.V. Broke commanding his Majesty's Ship Shannon, his Officers, Seamen & Marines, this representation of their gallantly boarding the American Frigate Chesapeak … Is most respectfully Inscribed by their Obt. Servant Robt. Dodd.", 1813 (Folder FF-29)
      Painted by Robt. Dodd from the information of Captn. Falkinir. Published August 1813 by R. Dodd and G. Andrews. First state. Second of a pair of prints. Colored by hand.
    - Print No. 203. Aquatint: "To Captain P.B.V. Broke commanding his Majesty's Ship Shannon...", 1813 (Folder FF-11)
      Full title: "To Captain P.B.V. Broke commanding his Majesty's Ship Shannon, his Officers, Seamen & Marines, this representation of their gallantly boarding the American Frigate Chesapeak, being 440. Men superior in force and hauling down the Enemy's Colours in fifteen Minutes from commencement of the Action. Is most respectfully Inscribed by their Obt. Servant Robt. Dodd." Published August 1813 by R. Dodd and G. Andrews. Second state of No. 202 supra, omitting painting reference to Robt. Dodd and Captn. Falkinir.
    - Print No. 205. Aquatint: "To Captain Broke, the Officers, Seamen and Marines of His Majesty's Ship Shannon,...", undated (Folder FF-21)
      Full title: "To Captain Broke, the Officers, Seamen and Marines of His Majesty's Ship Shannon, This View of their Boarding & Capturing the American United States Frigate The Chesapeake … is with respect Dedicated to them, and the Admirers of British Valor, by their obedient Servant, G. Webster." Painted by G. Webster under the direction of Captn. Falkner. Engraved by Jeakes. Published by G. Webster. First state. The second of a pair of prints.
    - Print No. 206. Aquatint: "To the Right Honorable Lord Viscount Melville… This Print of His Majesty's Frigate the Shannon, Captn. Broke, Commander, ...", 1813 (Folder FF-21)
      Full title: "To the Right Honorable Lord Viscount Melville… This Print of His Majesty's Frigate the Shannon, Captn. Broke, Commander, carrying the American Frigate, Chesapeake (Commanded by Capt. Lawrance) by boarding in sight of Boston Harbour is repectfully inscribed by … J. Hassell." Painted by Thomas Whitcombe. Aquatinted by Jeakes. Published Sept. 1, 1813 by Hassell & Co. First state, inscribed by J. Hassell.
    - Print No. 207. Aquatint: "To the Right Honorable Lord Viscount Melville …This print of His Majesty's Frigate the Shannon, Captn. Broke, Commander, carrying the American Frigate, Chesapeake, … is respectfully inscribed by J. Hassel, & Co.", undated (Folder FF-29)
      Painted by Thomas Whitcombe. Aquatinted by Jeakes. Second state, inscribed by J. Hassell & Co.
    - Print No. 208. Lithograph: "No. 1 … This representation of H.M.S. Shannon, commencing the Battle with the American Frigate Chesapeake, on the 1st. June 1813, is Dedicated by his obliged and most grateful Servant, R.H. King.", undated (Folder FF-29)